SAMEEHA RAHMAN

Colombo, Sri Lanka +94766369906 1rahman.sameeha@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/1sameeha-rahman https://samsam-026.github.io/ github.com/samsam-026

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | FULL STACK DEVELOPER

A degree-educated developer with two academic qualifications in the field, with working knowledge in many web and hybrid mobile technologies, such as React.js, Angular, React Native and Flutter. An engineer who stays up to date on recent technologies and inventions in the fields of science and technology, who constantly revises software best practices and user experience guidelines. A blogger at two popular online news platforms, with articles in multiple technical topics. An award-winning event organizer of hackathons, with experience in chairing tech conferences.

EDUCATION

B. Eng. Software Engineering | University of Westminster (2016 – Present)

Currently enrolled in the 4-year Software Engineering Course offered by the Informatics Institute of Technology, Colombo, Sri Lanka. Waiting for results, due in June 2020.

Level 4 (1st Year) Average: 84% (5 Distinctions and 1 Credit)

Level 5 (2nd Year) Average:79% (6 Distinctions)

Bachelor Diploma as Frontend Developer | OpenClassrooms (2019 – 2020)

OpenClassrooms is Europe's largest online education platform recognized as a higher education institution. The course is project-driven, focusing on students to learn by putting concepts into practice. It connects students with industry professionals for 1 to 1 mentorship on a weekly basis. Completed all 9 projects ranging from a WordPress application, an HTML-based game, to a React.js restaurant review website.

Advanced Level | Ilma International Girls School (2008 – 2016)

Cambridge GCE A/Level: 2 A* and 2 A. Cambridge GCE O/Level: 5 A*, 1 A and 1 B.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelancer | Capitol Overseas Courier Service (Pvt.) Ltd. (2017 – Present)

Designed and implemented the company website and invoicing and internal operation systems using ASP.NET Core technologies.

Technology: Classic ASP, Visual Basic, MSSQL, ASP .NET Core, React.js.

Intern | 99x Technology (Pvt.) Ltd. (2018 – 2019)

Working as a Software Engineering Intern on a cross-platform React Native mobile application. Designed and implemented the updated mobile app UI designs and setup the development pipeline using Jenkins.

Technology: React Native, Java, Node.js, MSSQL, Flutter.

Project Secretary | CodeSprint 3.0 Startup Battle (2017 – 2018)

Organized a month-long accelerator for start-ups created by University students in Sri Lanka, to pitch to investors and get funding for their technological solutions. Won Best Student Branch Activity at the 2018 IEEE Congress, Sri Lanka.

SKILLS

- o Great team worker and organizer with good communication skills.
- o Skilled in hybrid mobile technology, like React Native and Flutter, and created a React-Native UI component Library first-born.
- o Delivers work that is centered in User Experience (UX) guidelines.
- o Trained in web technologies and popular frameworks React.js and Angular.

TECHNOLOGIES AND TOOLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, React.js, React Native, Flutter, Ionic, Angular, Typescript, Bootstrap, Node.js, MongoDB, MSSQL, Firebase, ASP.NET, C#, Jest, Adobe Photoshop, Figma, Git.

ACTIVITIES

Projects

Developer | first-born (2019)

A React Native UI framework consisting of inbuilt components, developed the using Atomic design, with over 1000 downloads and over 200 stars on GitHub. This highly customizable library allows UI components to render separately according to the underlying platform, following platform UX guidelines, reducing the work of front-end developers.

Technology: React Native, Jest, ESLint.

Certifications

Google Mobile Sites (2018 – 2019) EF Standard English Test (C1 Advanced) (2016)

Competitions

Runner-Up | JumpStart - Achievers Lanka Business School (2017)

Finalist: 4th | CIMA Launch Pad – CIMA (2017)

Runner-Up | TadHack - hSenid Mobile (2017)

Runner-Up | BeThem Challenge – 99X Technology (2016)

REFERENCES

Mr. Guhanathan Poravi Senior Lecturer / Course Leader Informatics Institute of Technology 57, Ramakrishna Road, Wellawatte guhanathan.p@iit.ac.lk

+94773423330

Mr. Pumudu Fernando
Lecturer / Level Coordinator
Informatics Institute of Technology
57, Ramakrishna Road, Wellawatte
pumudu.f@iit.ac.lk